喂
Hello?
嘿  是我  我知道你不愿意和我一起住了
Hey, It's me. I know you can't stand to be in the same room as me,
但我还是想在电话里给你道歉  我…
I just thought I'd try and apologize over the phone...All I...
喂
Hello?
听着  我不该亲你的女朋友  但我…
Look, I never should've kissed your girlfriend, but I'm...
别再打来了
Stop calling!
嘿  这里是92.3摇滚广播电台
Hey! Hey! Hey! This is 92.3, WXRK, K-Rock...
来挑战我们每天的千元大奖吧
...calling with our $1000 daily challenge.
漂亮
All right.
请问你室友的名字是什么
What is the name of...
那个对你非常抱歉  愿意做任何事情
...your roommate who is very, very sorry and would do anything...?
《老友记》  第四季  第08集  闭关思过
Friends S04E08  The one with Chandler in a box
（主演：詹妮弗·安妮斯顿）
（主演：柯特妮·考克斯）
（主演：丽莎·库卓）
（主演：马特·勒布朗）
（主演：马修·派瑞）
（主演：大卫·修蒙）
啊  火鸡
Ugh, turkey.
啊  感恩  啊
Ugh, giving thanks. Ugh.
看  各位  这就是感恩节的精神
Look, everyone, it's the spirit of Thanksgiving.
你和乔伊好点了吗
So are things with you and Joey any better?
糟糕透了  昨晚我给他拨了8个小时的电话
They couldn't be worse. I spent eight hours calling him last night,
想让他和我说说话
just trying to get him to talk to me.
哇  8小时
Oh, wow. Eight hours.
你一定用的着那种配在电话上的小耳机
So you could probably really use one of those plug-in telephone headsets, huh?
我们都会收到  你从办公室偷来的圣诞礼物吗
Should we all expect Christmas gifts that can be stolen from your office?
没你的份
You shouldn't.
说到圣诞节
Speaking of Christmas...
摩妮卡和我刚开业  没什么钱
since Monica and I are starting a new business and have like no money...
今年可以来个秘密的圣诞  我们每人就买一个礼物
this year maybe we could do Secret Santa and then we each only buy one gift.
这样还多了个神秘感  看谁送给谁
And-and there's the added mystery of, you know, who gets who.
是谁抽到〝哪个人〞
Who gets "whom."
我不知道为什么这么做
I don't know why I do that.
我得睡一会  火鸡让我犯困了
Oh, I'm gonna take a nap. Turkey makes me sleepy.
我们还没吃那
We haven't eaten yet.
我知道  但你们一直在准备  那我就…
I know, but all that work you're doing to get it ready, and I just...
你们谁打算抽到瑞秋吗  因为我想送她个礼物
Hey, by any chance did either of pick uh Rachel for your secret Santa, Because I wanna trade for her.
我抽到她  谢天谢地幸好你要她
I picked her. Oh, thank God, you want her.Ooh!
为什么你这么不想送她礼物
Wow, why do you wanna get rid of her so badly?
因为她收到什么礼物都拿去换
Because she exchanges every gift she ever gets,
根本没法送给她她想要的东西
It's like impossible to get her something she likes.
来吧  咱俩换换
Come on, let's trade.
不会的  哪有这回事  她很喜欢我送她的那个背包的
That's not true. That's not true. I got her that backpack and she loved it.
记得有只大狗叼走的时候  她哭的多伤心…
I remember how much she was crying the day that big dog ran off with it…
根本没有什么大狗
There was no big dog.
不管这个了  我已经给她买了个皮包  还在上面印上了R.G…
All right this sucks, because I already got her this briefcase and I had "R.G." put on it.
是她的姓名缩写
Her initials. Oh.
也许你可以送给别人  像罗斯盖勒  一样的缩写
Maybe you can give it to somebody else. Oh. Like Ross Geller.
但那是个女用公事包
Oh, you know what, though? It's a girlie briefcase.
那又怎样  他在博物馆上班
Who cares? He works in a museum.
嘿  几点了  球赛要开始了
Hey, what time is it? The big game's about to start.
罗斯和乔伊又不在  没必要这样  愿意的话就看游行呗
You don't have to do that, Ross and Joey aren't here. watch the parade if you want.
谢了
Thanks.
这个冷冻室出什么毛病了  嗷  嗷
What is wrong with this freezer? Ow! Ow!
怎么了  天啊  冰渣进我眼睛了
God, what happened? Oh, my God, ice just got in my eye.
有人还想在这儿睡觉
People are trying to sleep in here.
摩妮卡的眼睛进冰渣了  很疼
Monica got ice in her eye and it hurts.
睁开  让我看看  不行  太疼了
Open it up. Let me see. Oh, I can't. It really kills.
或许应该冰敷
Well, maybe you should put some ice on it.
好像很严重  也许该送你去看医生
Ooh, it looks bad. Honey, Maybe we should take you to a doctor.
不行  我的眼科医生是理查
No, my eye doctor is Richard.
没有男朋友我不能去见他的
I can't go to him when I don't have a boyfriend.
他对病人的确够挑剔的
He's really picky about his patients.
你非去不可  他诊所电话号码是多少
Okay, you've gotta go. What's his office number?
我哪会记得
Oh, like I remember his office number.
试试快捷键7
Speed dial 7.
嗨  我是代表摩妮卡盖勒的眼睛在说话
Hi, yeah, I'm calling on behalf of Monica Geller's eye, and...
理查柏克今天在上班吗
Is Richard Burke in today?
他出城了   她愿意见其他随叫随到的医生么
He's out of town. but does she wanna see the on-call doctor?
愿意  愿意  她非常兴奋
Yes. Yes. She's very excited about that.
太酷了
This is so cool.
摩妮卡回来之前  我是主厨  所有决定都由我来做
Till Monica gets back, it's like I'm head chef and I get to make all the decisions.
嘿  嘿  我想她跟你说了  让你按照食谱来
Hey, hey, I thought she told you to follow the recipe exactly.
滚出我的厨房
Okay, get out of my kitchen.
好  我想我跟乔伊之间有进展了
All right, okay. I think I'm making some progress with Joey.
我进房的时候  他直接回他的卧室
When I went into the apartment, he went straight into his bedroom...
他只摔了一下门
...but he only slammed the door once!
不过摔门的时候  对我比了中指
I mean, yeah, he gave me the finger while doing it.
好吧  我得打电话问问我妈左撇子做菜的问题
All right I… I gotta call my mom and ask her a left-handed cooking question.
听着  我抽到送摩妮卡礼物
So listen, I picked Monica for Secret Santa...
但我光明节送过她了
...but I'm getting her something for Hanukkah.
你想和我换换
I was wondering if you wanna switch.
知道么  我是想要送给你
Oh y'know what, I was already trying to trade for ah, well, you.
真的  有意思  打算送我什么
Really?! Wow! That's so nice, what are you gonna get me?
不晓得  R.G  办公室里用的女式用品
I don't know, R.G. I was thinking something girlie for your office.
也许菲比愿意跟我换
Yeah. Well, maybe Phoebe will switch with me.
最好不要  那你会抽到瑞秋  她什么礼物都会拿去换
Oh no-no-no, you don't want to do that,Then you're gonna get stuck with Rachel, and she exchanges every gift she ever gets.
不可能  我送她很多东西她都留着的
Oh, that's not true. I got her lots of stuff she never took back.
比如
Like?
比如像我去年送的金项链
Like that gold necklace I got her last year.
你最后一次看到她带着是什么时候
When was the last time you saw her wear it?
她整个圣诞都带着  然后…
Well, she wore it all Christmas day and then, uh...
大狗
Big dog?
嘿  嘿
Hey. Hey.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
把钱德内疚买的东西全部退回去
Sending back all this stuff that Chandler bought out of guilt.
全部  包括电视  不  电视要搬进我房里
Everything? Even the TV? No, I'm put that in my room.
听着  乔伊  我知道他做错了
Listen, Joey. I know what he did was wrong.
但你就不能听他解释吗
But don't you think you could at least hear the guy out?
你和瑞秋在一起时
Back when you and Rachel were together...
要是钱德吻了她  你会听他解释吗
...if Chandler had kissed her, would you hear him out?
说得好
That's a good point.
那你要惩罚他多久
So uh, how long are you gonna punish him?
五年
Five years.
你在判他刑
You've sentenced him?
嘿  若要人不知  除非己莫为
Hey, don't do the crime if you can't do the time.
但是乔伊  他可是你最好的朋友  不  那是以前
But, Joey, the guy's your best friend. No, was my best friend.
你干嘛拼命替他说情
Anyway, I don't know why you're pushing for him so hard.
少了他  我"最要好的朋友"就空出来了
With him out of the way as my best friend, there's a spot open.
谁  我吗  对
Who, me? Yeah.
当然  真荣幸
Wow. I'm honored.
那么作为你最好的朋友  我该做的第一件事就是
And you know what I'm gonna do as my first act as your best friend?
我得让你去跟钱德说话
I'm gonna get you to talk to Chandler.
好啦
All right.
除非你是我最好的朋友…
Oh, but if you weren't my best friend...
天哪  真的那么严重
Oh, my God. Is it really that bad?
我进了门  他根本不理我
I walk in the room, and he won't even talk to me.
他只是用意大利语在那儿嘟囔
He just mumbles something in Italian.
我知道他只会那些骂人的词儿
And I know he only knows the bad words.
阿甘  有没有看到钱德
Hey, Gunther, have you uh, have you seen Chandler?
我以为你才是钱德
I thought you were Chandler.
你们其中一个在那边
But, um, one of you is over there.
嘿  乔伊
Hey, Joe.
请稍等一下  好吗
I'll be right with you, okay?
谢谢你
Thanks
天哪  这个代诊医生真帅
Oh, my God. How cute is the on-call doctor?
够帅啊  帅到我想拿笔插我的眼睛
Oh. So cute that I'm thinking about jamming this pen in my eye.
柏克医生在等你
Dr. Burke will see you now.
不  不   柏克医生不在  出城去了
Oh, no, no, no, not Dr. Burke. Dr. Burke's out of town.
现在我要看的是另一个医生
The on-call doctor will see me now.
理查柏克医生不在
Dr. Richard Burke is out of town.
他儿子提摩西柏克医生帮你看
Dr. Timothy Burke, his son, will see you now.
准备好了吗
Ready?
对不起  刚才…
Hey, I'm sorry. That...
你要去哪里  我爸妈家
Where you going? My folks'.
什么时候回来
Oh, uh, when-when are you coming back?
不知道
I don't know.
待一段时间  顺便再去找个新房子住
I might stay there for a few days while I look for an apartment.
什么
What?
原先我以为我们可以谈开来  然后和好
Yeah, you know, at first I thought we could talk about this, work it out.
但一看到你俩在一起  我就……
but uh, seeing you two together I don't think I…
那你想让我说什么  说我不去见她了吗
Hey, look, what do you want me to say? Do you want me to say I'll stop seeing her?
跟她无关  好吗
Look, It's not about her. Okay?
一看到你俩  就让我想起你的所作所为
But seeing you two together just reminds me of what you did.
我不跟一个不懂朋友道义的人  住在一起
And I don't wanna live with someone who doesn't know what it is to be a friend.
我告辞了  我懂朋友道义
So I'll see you. Hey, look, I know what it is to be a friend.
我只是  只是搞砸了  对  没错
I just-I just screwed up! Yeah, you did.
所以我要搬走
And that's why I'm leaving.
听着  你不为我留下来  至少要为它们留下来
All right look, if you're not gonna stay for me, then at least stay for them.
它们这一年很不顺  还有那次抢劫
Okay? They have had a very difficult year, what with the robbery and all.
那个家伙在抢我们东西的时候
When that guy was robbing us...
我在柜子里被关了六小时
...and I was locked in the entertainment unit for six hours...
你知道我当时在干嘛吗
do you know what I was doing in there all that time?
我是在想  我多么的对不起你
I was thinking about how I let you down.
对
Wow. Yeah.
早知道你会见色忘友  我根本不会那样做
Yeah! But if would've know what kind of friend you were gonna turn out to be, I wouldn't have worried about it so much!
再见
See you around.
等一下   再给我个机会
Just wait one second. There has to be something that I can do.Something!
要是还有那个柜子
If we still had that entertainment unit...
我宁愿在里面待上6个小时  检讨我是怎样的对不起你
...I would get in there for six hours and think about how I let you down.
怎么了
What?
这儿有个箱子
We got a box.
我记得上次见到你
I remember the last time I saw you.
是我离家去学校的那天早上
It was the morning I left for college.
你站在乳品皇后店外面
And You were just standing outside the Dairy Queen.
可能是在等它开门
Heh. Just probably waiting for it to open.
我得说  你现在好漂亮
I gotta tell you, you look great now.
你也很帅  你真是个与众不同的病人
You look great too. You're an excellent patient.
伤痕明显么
So how does it look?
角膜上还有点伤  你得带个眼罩保护两三天
You've got a little scratch on your cornea. You're gonna have to wear a patch for a couple of days.
像海盗那样
Like a pirate?
大致是那样
If that helps you.
你跟你爸一起工作多久了
Ahem. So how long have you been working with your dad?
别这样  咱俩总有一个要提起他
Come on, one of us had to mention him.
两个月前搬回来的
I moved back here a couple months ago.
晚上有个家庭聚餐吧
Oh. Big family dinner tonight?
不是吧
No way.
我本来打算在女朋友家过感恩节的
I was gonna have Thanksgiving at my girlfriend's.
但我们分手了
Oh. But we broke up.
她对恋爱本身态度并不严肃
She-she wasn't ready for a serious commitment.
所以你把她从甲板上弄下去了  是吧  水手
Oh. So you made her walk the plank, aye, matey?
你还没带上眼罩呢
You're not wearing the patch yet.
我知道
I know.
他要来我们这儿过感恩节  对啊  好变态啊
He's coming here for Thanksgiving? I know. It's sick.
为什么变态  因为他是理查的儿子
Why is it sick? Because it's Richard's son.
简直是把希腊悲剧故事邀请来了
It's like inviting a Greek tragedy over for dinner.
菲比  你理解我  对吧
Hey, come on, Phoebe, you understand, don't you?
可以说是  但做为你好友就得说  不
Yeah, I can see where I'd be your best shot but, no.
对不起  但我认为你把事情弄乱了
I'm sorry, but I think it's twisted.
什么事儿乱了  我跟理查的儿子约会
What's twisted? Oh. Me going out with Richard's son.
好嗯
Ewwwww!!
嗯 嗯 嗯
Ew, ew, ew.
听起来是不怎么样
Sounds like a really bad idea to me.
他在里面没事儿吧
Is he okay in there?
他很好
He's fine.
要是你跟理查的儿子真的成了
Hey, y'know, Mon, if things wrong out between you and Richard's son, ...
你就能对你们的孩子说  你和他们的祖父上过床
...you'll be able to tell your kids that you slept with their grandfather.
好  随你们怎么批评  不过
Fine! Judge all you want to but,
和女同性恋结婚  临阵逃婚  迷上滑冰舞的同性恋
married a lesbian, left a man at the altar, fell in love with a gay ice dancer...
把女生的木腿丢进火里  住在箱子里
...threw a girl's wooden leg in the fire, live in a box.
那么  这个箱子是什么用意
So, now, ahem, what exactly is the point of the box?
钱德
Chandler?
箱子的用意有三点
The meaning of the box is three fold.
一是  让我有时间好好反思我的所作所为
One, it gives me the time to think about what I did.
二是  说明我是多么在乎跟乔伊的友谊
Two, it proves how much I care about my friendship with Joey.
三是
And three
会痛
it hurts.
嘿  喔
Oh, hey, hey, uh... Hmm?
还记得我去年送你的项链吗
you remember the necklace I gave you last year?
能给我看看么
Can I see it?
为什么
Why?
只是想看看而已
I just wanna check something.
好
Okay.
等着瞧吧
Now we'll see.
没气了  没气了
Air hole! Air hole!
在这里  我很喜欢  整天带着
Here it is. I love it. I wear it all the time.
我送你的是金项链  这个是银的
The necklace I got you was gold. this is silver.
也许它
Huh. Well, maybe, it, uh
变色了
it changed.
天哪  你真的把它给换了
Oh, my God. You actually exchanged it.
换一个我喜欢又常用的东西
Well isn't it better that I exchanged it for something that I enjoy
这样不好吗
and that I can get a lot of use out of?
你换了什么
What did you get?
存款
Credit.
我来开  我来开  我来开
I'll get it, I'll get it, I'll get it.
嗨  提姆  嗨
Hi, Tim. Hi.
嗨  谢谢  来见见我的朋友
Hi. Thank you. Come meet my friends.
这是菲比  幸会
This is Phoebe. Hi, nice to meet you.
乔伊  你好
And Joey. Hey.
乔伊  我哥哥罗斯
Joey. My brother, Ross.
你好  还有瑞秋
Hey. And Rachel.
你好
Hi. Ahem.
那是钱德  你好
That's Chandler. How do you do?
这是  他在
What's...? Um, well, he's, um...
他在反省
He's doing some thinking.
他得分了
He's got it.
耶  耶
Yes! Yeah!
怎么了  怎么了  你亲了我的女友
What happened? What happened?! You kissed my girlfriend.
喔  我喜欢那些太阳镜
Ooh, I like those sunglasses.
"真的喜欢"  还是喜欢它们
"Like them" like them...
还是喜欢它们带来的存款
...or "I'd like to get store credit for that amount" like them?
好了各位  火鸡上桌了
All right, everybody. This turkey is ready.
在哪洗手  这里
Where can I wash up? Here.
我带你去
Let me show you.
毛巾在水池旁边  你能用那块高级香皂
Okay, the towels are hanging next to the sink, and umm, you can use the fancy soap.
谢谢
Thank you.
高级香皂  我还以为是为教皇准备的
Fancy soap? I thought we were saving that for the Pope.
他不错  是吧
See? He's nice, right?
是的  不过莫妮卡  你是否想过发展下去  就能这么说了
Yeah, but Monica, do you actually want to be in a relationship where you can actually use the phrase,
"你父亲以前可不这么做"
"That's not how your dad used to do it"?
哇  真丰盛  我坐哪儿
Wow, everything looks great. Where should I sit?
我帮你留了个位子
Saved you a seat.
变态-变态-变态-变态
Sick-sick-sick-sick.
我来开门
Oh, I'll get it.
被我骗了
Gotcha.
这听起来不像是在为我反思
That doesn't sound like thinking to me.
对不起  我可不认为你应该说话
Sorry. Y'know I don't think you should be talking at all in there!
要反思那么多事情  应该没空说话和开玩笑的
I think you got too much thinking to do to be talking and making jokes.
好  好  遵命
Okay, okay, you got it.
罗斯  递给我红薯  好么
Ross, could you pass me the yams? Sure.
你想换的话  乔伊那里还有土豆泥
Oh, and Joey's got the mashed potatoes if you want to exchange them.
够了  你到底怎么了
Will you stop? What is the matter with you?
有客人喔
Oh-ho-ho, We've got company.
我没什么事儿
There's nothing the matter with me.
可我不缺乏情感
See, I'm not completely devoid of sentiment.
我有感受的
See, I have feelings.
好  很好
Okay, fine.
你们都哑巴了吧  我来缓解一下气氛
You can't tell, but I'm trying to break the tension by mooning you guys.
好  听着
All right, look.
如果你把它当成笑话  那就算了  好吗
If this is just a big joke to you, then forget about it, all right?
这对我不是玩笑
This means something to me.
你要是觉得无所谓  那你马上走
And if it doesn't mean anything to you, then you should get out of there.
除非你是个愿意呆在箱子里的傻瓜
Otherwise, you're just an idiot in a box.
你说的对  我错了  这事对我很重要
You're right. I'm sorry. This means a lot to me.
我要让你重新成为我的朋友  我发誓  今晚不再说一个字了
I want you to be my friend again. I swear I won't say another word tonight.
你真的会当回事  绝对会
So you're gonna take this thing seriously? Absolutely.
又说话了
That sounds like another word to me.
你真的会当一回事吗
Are you gonna take this seriously?
很好
Okay.
不要说我没有情感啊
Don't say that I have no sentiment.
这是第一次  我们约会的电影票根
This is a movie stub from our first date.
这是第一次  你为我做床上早点的蛋壳
This is an eggshell from the first time you made me breakfast in bed.
这是从博物馆的拿  我们第一次…
This is from the museum, the first time we...
在一起的时候
...were together.
对  也许我是常把礼物换掉  但有意义的东西我会留
Okay, maybe I exchange gifts sometimes, but I keep the things that matter.
我不知道该说什么好  对不起
I don't know what to say. I'm sorry.
不过
Though
你不该把这个拿走
you're not supposed to take these.
它有差不多百万年的历史
It's like a million years old.
事实上  我们还派专人去找过的
we, we actually, we had people looking for that.
老是会卡住
Oh, this always happens.
让我来
Here, let me, um...
谢谢
Thank you.
你有非常漂亮的
You-you have a very beautiful
眼睛
eye.
所有的朋友都认为这事儿很怪
Y'know all my friends think this is weird.
我原先也觉得会  还差点打电话取消  但事实上不会
Y'know I-I thought it was gonna be weird, I mean I almost called and canceled, but it really isn't.
我的意思是咱们现在  我与你父亲的过去  完全是两码子事情
I know. I mean, it's like me and your dad, that's a totally separate thing.
完全同意
Oh, I totally agree.
我是说  我们只是两个
we're just two people who find each other
互相吸引的人
very attractive.
对吧
Right?
怎么了  没事  没事
What? Nothing, nothing.
真的  吻的不好
No, no, really. Oh, was-was that not okay?
不  很好
No, no, no, that was good.
那是个  呃  甜蜜的吻
That was, uh... That was a good kiss.
天啊  这不会让你想起  别说了
Oh, my God. It didn't remind you of my...? Oh, don't say it.
但是有  对吧  对
No, but it did! Didn't it?! Yes!
欧  天哪
Oh, man.
我知道
I know.
我去开
I got it.
嘿   嘿
Hey. Hey.
听着  我真的很抱歉   没关系
Hey. Listen, I want you to know how sorry I am... It's okay.
没事儿  我气的是钱德
That's okay. Chandler's the one I'm mad at. so...
我还是很抱歉
Well, I'm so sorry.
他在吗  在箱子里
Is he here? In the box.
钱德
Chandler?
他现在不能说话
Oh, he can't talk right now.
为什么  怎么了
Why not? What's going on?
他在向乔伊证明他是多么在乎他
He's just trying to show Joey how much he means to him.
所以窝在箱子里  乔伊有他的理由
By being in a box? Joey had reasons.
有三个理由
They were threefold.
啊  哦  好吧
Oh. Well, uh...
你不能讲话  这样倒也好
you not being able to talk may make this easier.
听我说…
Listen, um
听我说
Listen.
我不想介入两个最要好的朋友之间
I don't wanna be someone who comes between two best friends.
我真不忍心看到会发生在你们身上的事情
I just... I can't stand seeing what this is doing to you guys.
也不想是因为我  所以
And I don't wanna be the cause of that.So
我想我们还是不要见面了
I don't think we can see each other anymore.
我要去芝加哥找我妈
I'm gonna go to my mom's in Chicago.
我会住一阵子
I'm gonna stay there for a while.
这么做或许让人感到惊讶
I think this could have been something really amazing.
但你知道  或许这么做最好
But, you know, this is probably for the best.
你懂吗
You know?
我会想念你的
I'm gonna miss you.
再见了  钱德
Goodbye, Chandler.
把箱子打开
Open the box.
什么  他还能追上她
What? He can still catch her.
出来  出来  出来
Hey, come on. Get out of there. Get out of there.
那么  咱们俩没事啦  出来啦
So...? Yeah, we're gonna be fine. Get out.
真的   对
Yeah? Yeah.
你好好反省过了
Yeah, You did some real good thinking in there.
这真是…
I mean, this is...
赶紧走  你还能追上她
Now go. You could still catch her.
因为我的秘密圣诞是给你的
And merry Christmas from your Secret Santa.
谁抽到钱德了  我要换
All right, who got Chandler? Because I need to trade.
他看到她了
Oh, he sees her.
他在追她
Aw, and he's catching up to her.
她看到他了
Oh, she sees him.
他们拥抱了
Oh, they're hugging. Aw.
他在拿她的钱包
He's taking her purse.
不是他们  我去报警
Uh, that's not them. I'm gonna go call the police.
喔  他们在那里  哪里
Oh, there they are. Where?
好  快去开房吧
All right, get a room.